This page is now deprecated. Please do not update!

Anyone can describe, tag, recommend, comment on and annotate services

Expert curators oversee the BioCatalogue

The wider community participates in this effort through social curation

Annotating Web Services in the BioCatalogue

Web Service annotation can be defined as specific piece of metadata(text, image etc…) associated with a specific aspect of the Web Service. The annotations may be context specific and can be designed for human or for machine.
The point of the annotation is to describe services and their components (operation, resources, inputs, outputs etc.) so that users or programs can find and use them.

Who can annotate?

Any registered user (Member) can annotate any service in the BioCatalogue whether they submitted it or not. Click here to become a Member of the BioCatalogue.
Annotation can take the form of free text, tags, terms from selected ontology and examples values.

Web Service annotation best practice

1-Where is the documentation?

The first thing to consider when you are annotating a service is to point to its documentation. In the BioCatalogue you can use one or several URLs to point to the service documentation.

2-What is it about?

Define the purpose of the service. Clearly describe what the service does by giving clear and simple details of what the service is meant to do. In the BioCatalogue use the description field provided. Add tags to the service.

3-Can anyone use it?

People will use a service if they find it useful. Are there any restrictions such as licenses, usage restriction applied to the service? Highlight them. In the BioCatalogue use the required fields such as license, cost, usage restriction to highlight them.

4-Who to contact?

State the contact details of the provider of the service or the support team. This could be an e-mail address or a feedback form. In the BioCatalogue use the contact info field.

5-What does the operation do or what are the resources?

Clearly describe each of the operations for SOAP services or the resources for REST services. In the BioCatalogue, you can access SOAP Web Services operation description field from the operation tab. Note that you can tag individual operation.

6-What is the input?

Clearly describe each of the operations inputs and provide example values. State the input formats. Note that example values are very important. They can later be used to test the service. In the BioCatalogue use the fields provide for input description, data format and examples for these information. Note that you can tag individual inputs.

7-What is the output?

Clearly describe the output and provide examples. Also mention the format of the output. In the BioCatalogue use the fields provide for output description, data format and examples for these information. Note that you can tag individual output.

Remarks

You can assign one or more category to your services based on their functions.

You can give an alternative name to your service and promote it as a default service display name.

You can update the service provider profile

Date: Monday 6th Apr 2009

Time: 15:00-16:00 (UK)

Telcon No: 08445805588

Pin: 70503010

Attending

Manchester: Carole, Jiten

EBI: Eric, Franck, Thomas

Apologies

Rodrigo

Minuting

Eric

Agenda

Actions from the last telcon

Should we have a BioCatalogue Google Calendar (like myGrid do) for people to put holidays, events and so on?

Post SAB

Are we happy with the minutes?

Are there any other tasks missing that we need to consider?

Possible collaboration with Microsoft-meeting with Rudy

Progress/developement of the pilot - are we rolling?

Test infrastructure setup at EBI and progress of service testing/monitoring piece.

What terms/ontologies should we use to seed tags?

First step is to use controlled control vocabulary terms

Possible of share of ontology sourcing work between my experiment/sysmo/

Technical meeting

Summary of tasks on Rubyforge

BioCatalogue support review

20 Questions analysis

Actions from Previous Meeting

Franck: submit ISMB demo abstract by 20th April. [done]

Carole: to talk at the BioIT meeting about our policy. [ on going]

Rodrigo: DDBJ, NCBI – ownership and diplomacy. [on going]

Franck: sourcing from ontology to be added to the task list.[ done ]

Jits: create a mailing list for the SAB team. [done ]

Franck: sort out wording for policies/disclaimers/conditions and figure out a plan on where to put these on the site, and where users need to be notified of these.[action taken forward ]

Jits: make his notes from the SAB meeting (incl new tasks identified) available.

Rodrigo, Franck: update the SAB minutes and make them more comprehensive minutes.

Carole: ring BBSRC programme manager to inform her that the SAB has taken place and then see what they have to say.[ role over ]

Jits: send example FETA XML files to list, to show an example of what kind of metadata is in them.

Carole: to dig out MS Word + OBOE plugin/tool. [done]

Steve, Eric: provide an update on what is happening with the test scripts execution environment.[ Eric talking to EBI systems to have test machine/ background processing for pinging to be done by Eric/ priorities monitoring API]

Minutes

BioCatalogue Google Calendar has been set up for people to put holidays, events and so on.

On Post SAB

Minutes are still to be formalized. Thomas to work with Franck to produce SAB minutes

Are there any other tasks missing that we need to consider?

Carole is in contact with Rudy for collaboration with Microsoft

Expected update of the BioCatalogue beta site has been moved to after easter

Eric is talking to EBI systems poeple on the possibilities of setting up a similar framework to the EMBRACE test environment at EBI. Further details expected after the easter break. There is need to reconsider the priorities of the monitoring API, both for the long term and in case concerns raised by EBI on the current EMBRACE registry monitoring approach are not met.

On terms/ontologies

First step is to use controlled control vocabulary terms

There is a possibility to share ontology sourcing work between myExperiment, BioCatalogue & Sysmo

Action Items

Thomas, Franck: update the SAB minutes and make them more comprehensive minutes.

Carole: ring BBSRC programme manager to inform her that the SAB has taken place and then see what they have to say.

Eric: provide an update on what is happening with the test scripts execution environment.

Update on decision on the script running environment

Investigate background processing for long running tasks

Re-prioritize work on the API for service monitoring

Franck & Eric : Produce elaborate document on the BioCatalogue data model [ Annotation + Information ]

All : Decide on how to go forward with the ratings [ on whether we make that available to the public at this stage or not]

Upcoming Meetings

Biocuration meeting 16-19 april

ISMB - we have a poster accepted

AOB

Should we change the meeting date?

Previous/Next Meetings

Previous meeting: Phone Conference Meeting on Mar 30 2009

Next meeting: Phone Conference Meeting on Apr 20 2009

Discovering Web Services in the BioCatalogue

The Problem: “Web Services are hard to find…”

So…

Find the right Web Service using the BioCatalogue

We offer easy and powerful search and filtering interfaces

We index metadata made available by service providers, expert curators and the wider community

When searching for services in the BioCatalogue there is an auto suggestion based on the content of the catalogue and previous searches by users. Search terms are case insensitive and can be combined with AND. e.g. Blast AND Protein

In addition, when searching for bioinformatic terms e.g. microarray, the BioCatalogue will automatically include in your search query any related terms e.g. affymetrix, probeset, etc. The myGrid ontology is used to define the relationship between terms.

Search by Data

You can search for services that might analyse or process your data using the search for data feature. For example, given a sequence in fasta format, it returns a list of services that possibly consume sequences in fasta format.
The “Search by data” depends on example inputs and outputs of service operations in BioCatalogue. It is based on the FileQuirks algorithm.

Service filtering

Web Services in the BioCatalogue can be filtered by:

Service type: SOAP or REST

Service category: services are grouped based on their functions.

Service provider: e.g NCBI, EBI, DDBJ

Submitter: registries or Members who submitted the service

Country of Origin: where is the service hosted.

If you enable the tag filter, you can also filter services by:

Tags on services

Tags on service operations

Tags on service inputs

Tags on service outputs

Note that you can combine different filter. e.g.

F2F design-a-thon 14th-15th August 2008 @ EBI, Cambridge

Attending

Thomas, Eric, Hamish, Katy, Franck, Jits, Don, Sergejs

Note: Jits is also there Mon 18th and Tues 19th.

Expected Outcomes

This needs more clarification!

Content requirements

Design document of the system

Beginnings of code

Clear and unambiguous definitions and documentation on requirements, what components to use, what is 'in' myExperiment, what is 'in' BioCatalogue, a plan and so on.

Some information on expected performance, scalability, support and so on for the pilot.

Agenda

Day 1

Manchester people arriving at EBI around 11:30am

12:00pm - lunch, 12:30pm start, 5:00pm finish.

myExperiment show and tell, and questions (Jits, Don, Sergejs)

EB-eye show and tell, and questions (Franck Valentin)

Current work show and tell, and questions (Thomas, Eric)

Discuss high level architecture of pilot, taking into account integration with other pieces/systems (All)

Day 2

9:30am start, 5:00pm finish, lunch in between.

Discuss and finalise functional requirements for the pilot solution (this includes detailing definitions and terms) (All)

Discuss and finalise initial content requirements for the pilot solution (All)

Brainstorm designs for key aspects of the pilot solution (this includes integration pieces and strategies for the integration) (All)

Put together a development plan (All)

Put together information on expected performance, scalability, support and so on for the pilot solution (All)

Actions

myExperiment team to investigate putting stuff into plugins, e.g: user authentication, reviews/ratings, (upcoming) event logging and (upcoming) discussion threads.

Ask Stian about the Feta service browser.

Jits to speak to Franck, Katy and Stian about Ontologies to be used in BioCatalogue.

Management to decide on license for source code.

Jits and Eric to come up with proposed designs for the core data model and other core features, before hackfest in Southampton.

Decisions

Development tasks coordinated between developers (especially for parallel tasks).

Use RubyForge to host the source code.

Rails v2.1 will be used.

Source code license: TBD

We will be writing tests for core functionality, especially basic unit and functional tests.

User Types

From a service provider's perspective there are three broad categories of user, with lots of overlap and a forth type of usage which cuts across all user types.

1. End User

Each use of the service is effectively in isolation

Access is via a user interface, most often via an HTML form or an application GUI, although some use is command-line orientated.

Domain knowledge is often high, but may not extend to the specifics of the service used.

Example:

Bench scientist with a sequence to analyse

Database curator with an entry to annotate

2. Developer

Producing applications/workflows which use one or more services

Domain knowledge often low. This is counterbalanced by the use of domain experts in testing and feature requests.

Service knowledge limited to that provided in the documentation

Service usage guidelines and examples are most useful to this group

3. Systematic User

Automated bulk analysis in workflows and scripts

User responsible for these processes may not be the workflow designer or process developer so domain and service knowledge can be very variable.

Service behaviour important to this group specifically:

Reliability: is the service going to be there for the 1st job and the 1000st job?

Stability: is the service going to be different tomorrow?

Consistency: are the results I get today comparable with the results I got yesterday?

Updatedness: is this the current stable version of the software, is it using the current releases of the databases?

Service documentation:

Announcements: downtime, problems, new versions, etc.

Usage policies: what are the limitations on service usage (e.g. max number of parallel processes, max. number of submissions per day, etc.).

4. Teaching

Demonstration/illustration of service usage

Students perform one of the other roles above (end-user, developer and/or systematic user), however the class as a whole behaves more like a systematic user

Service behaviour important to this group specifically:

Reliability: is the service going to be available while teaching?

Stability/consistency: are the results I get today different from those the students will get tomorrow?

Service documentation:

Announcements: downtime, version changes, retirement

Course guidelines: E.g. read the help, don't submit all at the same time, use suitable input data, search suitable databases, be considerate, etc.

Background Processing

Tasks That Require Background Processing

Stats generation

Soaplab server submission

Updating the annotation counts

Solr optimisation

Running the service monitoring URLs checks

Updating the list of urls that should be monitoring

Sending out monitoring status change emails

Info

Delayed::Job

Home - FAQ

Background job processing in Rails with delayed_job (blog post)

Handling Long-Running Tasks in Rails (presentation)

The New Queue (blog post)

rubyqueues - delayed_job (examples of using delayed_job)

Running Delayed::Worker as a daemon

Summary

(from: http://github.com/igal/rubyqueues/tree/master/delayed_job_eg/ [2009-06-04])

A pure Ruby plugin for Rails that uses the Rails database as a queue and runs jobs from it by polling.

Website: tobi's Delayed::Job

PROS: Easy to setup and use. Can create jobs from methods or objects. Automatically handles serialization of complex objects. Includes friendly job runner, which catches exceptions and retries failed jobs. Queue is as scalable as your database.

CONS: Rails only. Slow and uses polling, not appropriate for fast turnaround or high-volume messaging.

EVALUATION: A good choice for most message queuing needs within Rails applications.

Misc

Expiring Rails cache from a background task

Dev Notes

Using: delayed_job plugin

Concepts

Queue - the list of jobs that need to be run (together with priority and schedule info).

Jobs - particular tasks that do something.

Worker - aka job runner - the thing that executes the tasks.

Overall Runtime Process

Submit job → Job gets queued → Worker picks up job → Worker executes job → If successful then worker removes job from queue, else keeps job in queue for next run.

Queue Table

create_table :delayed_jobs, :force => true do |table|
  table.integer  :priority, :default => 0      # Allows some jobs to jump to the front of the queue
  table.integer  :attempts, :default => 0      # Provides for retries, but still fail eventually.
  table.text     :handler                      # YAML-encoded string of the object that will do work
  table.text     :last_error                   # reason for last failure (See Note below)
  table.datetime :run_at                       # When to run. Could be Time.now for immediately, or sometime in the future.
  table.datetime :locked_at                    # Set when a client is working on this object
  table.datetime :failed_at                    # Set when all retries have failed (actually, by default, the record is deleted instead)
  table.string   :locked_by                    # Who is working on this object (if locked)
  table.timestamps
end

Jobs and Job Submission

Any async/background task SHOULD be wrapped in a Job class that goes under /lib/bio_catalogue/jobs/. Be sure to follow the Rails' naming conventions for files in the /lib folder (ie: the file: /lib/bio_catalogue/jobs/my_job should correspond to a Ruby class or module BioCatalogue::Jobs::MyJob)

Submission of jobs to the queue for processing later - the preferred way to do this is to add a rake task to the file /lib/tasks/submit_jobs.rake that uses Delayed::Job.enqueue to queue a Job mentioned above. This rake task can then be run as part of a cronjob or created as part of user interaction or whatever else.

More information from the Delayed::Job documentation pages on how to use Delayed::Job specifically is below…

(from: http://github.com/tobi/delayed_job/tree/master [2009-06-04])

Jobs are simple ruby objects with a method called perform. Any object which responds to perform can be stuffed into the jobs table. Job objects are serialized to yaml so that they can later be resurrected by the job runner.

class NewsletterJob < Struct.new(:text, :emails)
  def perform
    emails.each { |e| NewsletterMailer.deliver_text_to_email(text, e) }
  end    
end

Delayed::Job.enqueue NewsletterJob.new('lorem ipsum...', Customers.find(:all).collect(&:email))

There is also a second way to get jobs in the queue: send_later.

BatchImporter.new(Shop.find(1)).send_later(:import_massive_csv, massive_csv)

This will simply create a Delayed::PerformableMethod job in the jobs table which serializes all the parameters you pass to it. There are some special smarts for active record objects which are stored as their text representation and loaded from the database fresh when the job is actually run later.

Extra info from FAQ:

To submit a job to run later (say after 5 minutes):

Delayed::Job.enqueue(NewsletterJob.new('text', User.find(:all).collect(&:email)), 0, 5.minutes.from_now)

Where 0 is the priority.

Running the Jobs

The following command runs the current jobs that are in the queue:

rake jobs:work

This has been wrapped into a script that makes it work as a daemon (ref: http://wiki.github.com/tobi/delayed_job/running-delayedworker-as-a-daemon). This allows you to run:

ruby script/worker start|stop|run|restart

… to manage workers and have them run continuously. This also allows us to spawn multiple workers (maybe on multiple machines), if required.

NOTE: workers always run in production mode. So if you are testing locally then ensure that your database config has the same database for both development and production modes (though it is not recommend to keep this config at all times!)

So, to start:

ruby script/worker start

.. and to stop:

ruby script/worker stop

Also, to test that the worker script is starting successfully, either check the logfile:

/tmp/pids/biocatalogue_worker.log

or:

/tmp/pids/biocatalogue_worker.output

… or run the worker script using the following:

ruby script/worker start -t

Every time you do an update to the servers (or locally), you need to restart the worker script! As that way the worker will run on the latest codebase (incl picking up the latest Jobs).

If things don't seem right with the background processing, check the delayed_jobs table. Failed jobs stay in there and are logged.

If too many jobs are piling up in this table then they should be cleared (otherwise all of them will be carried out!):

rake jobs:clear

Log File

The log file and output for the worker daemon are stored under tmp/pids/ as:

biocatalogue_worker.log

biocatalogue_worker.output

Anything that happens in the background worker that takes place in the Rails application should also write to the production/development logs in log/

Current Jobs

Name | Class | Info | Submission
CalculateAnnotationCountsJob | BioCatalogue::Jobs::CalculateAnnotationCountsJob | Goes through all the Services in the database and calculates
the total annotation counts (including grouped totals) and caches
them (see biocat_main.rb for cache time)

Internally, it just reuses the
BioCatalogue::Annotations::metadata_counts_for_service(service)
method, which takes care of the caching etc.
Currently, the counts data is cached for 60 mins.

| Rake task:

rake biocatalogue:submit:calculate_annotation_counts RAILS_ENV=production

Cron job should run this rake task every 45 mins.
UpdateUrlsToMonitor | BioCatalogue::Jobs::UpdateUrlsToMonitor | Create a listing of all the urls (service endpoints and wsdl location)
to monitor at the first run. Subsequent runs only make an update to the
list with nee service urls | rake biocatalogue:submit:update_urls_to_monitor RAILS_ENV=production
CheckUrlStatus | BioCatalogue::Jobs::CheckUrlStatus | Check the status of a url (endpoint or wsdl location). For soap endpoint,
some data is pointed to the file, expecting to get soap fault (xml) back.
For other urls, http head is obtained and status code is checked.
200 & 302 are OK, any other code triggers a warning | rake biocatalogue:submit:check_url_status RAILS_ENV=production
UpdateSearchQuerySuggestions | BioCatalogue::Jobs::UpdateSearchQuerySuggestions | Updates the file data/search_query_suggestions.txt with new terms from
search queries that user's have carried out.

Internally, it just reuses the
BioCatalogue::Search.update_search_query_suggestions_file
method. | Rake task:

rake biocatalogue:submit:update_search_query_suggestions RAILS_ENV=production

Cron job should run this rake task anywhere between
once an hour to every 3 hours.
UpdateAnnotationPropertiesFull | BioCatalogue::Jobs::UpdateAnnotationPropertiesFull | Updates the properties of the annotations
First the regular expressions are loaded from /data/regex.txt
and synchronized with the database
Secondly all annotations of examle inputs and outputs for SoapServices are cheched
against all regular expressions and matches are stored
| rake biocatalogue:submit:update_annotation_properties_full

Cron job should run this rake task from once a day to once a week
Wherever some regexes are deleted from the file,
this job should be run in shutdown time
RunServiceUpdater | BioCatalogue::Jobs::RunServiceUpdater | For a given Service, runs any update mechanisms that are required to update the state of that Service.
This can include things like WSDL sync methods and automatic curation. | Rake task:

none
RunServiceUpdateCheckerForAll | BioCatalogue::Jobs::RunServiceUpdaterForAll | Same as RunServiceUpdater but runs for ALL the services in the catalogue. | Rake task:

rake biocatalogue:submit:run_service_updater_for_all RAILS_ENV=production

Cron job should run this rake task every week or so.

Date: Tuesday 13th Jan 2008

Time: 15:00-16:00 (UK)

Telcon No: 08445805588

Pin: 70503010

Attending

Manchester: Jits, Carole

EBI:

Eric, Rodrigo, Thomas

Apologies

Frank, Katy, Hamish

Minuting

Eric

Agenda

New Year Stories

Actions from the last telcon

Progress with the pilot

New requirements and planning following the F2F at EBI

20 Questions(to clarify user requirements)

Discuss the “tag types” (freeform, from ontology, from CV etc) mentioned by Carole

Updating the BioCatalogue public wiki

AOB

Actions from Previous Meeting

Franck : Provide an example of a semantically annotated service(using the SAWSDL model).

Thomas: investigate 'home' link on the public wiki.

Jits/Thomas/Eric: create developer section on the wiki.

Eric: list the features of the current pilot (including annotations stuff), so that they can be used in a email announcing the private beta to the friends list.

Franck: read through the revised requirements and planning doc and update the private wiki roadmap accordingly. Then after approval copy it to the public wiki.

Franck: make an announcement about latest changes to schedule to the friends list.

Thomas: possibly change the “Wiki” link on the main website and beta site to something more descriptive like “More info about the project”. Also add this to the “About us” page.

Minutes

The beta site has been updated with the annotation functionality. This now permits annotations to be added to the inputs and outputs of operations

Eric & Jits are modeling rest services backend. Model is abstract so that it can handle both wadl and wsdl 2.0 or any other specifications that we may have to support

Work done on solr server interfacing with the application to enhance the search and remove some quirkiness of the plugin

Updates have been made to the wiki on the road map and the new requirements (following the F2F at EBI). The target is to have a development freeze at the end of February, in order to enable consolidation in March and public

People to come up with a set of 20 questions that would help clarify user requirements. My experiment is also doing this exercise so there is room to share some of the (relevant) questions. The answers to some of these question could be used to enrich the interface or even drive some of the design decisions

There a suite of NCBO tools that could be very useful for BioCatalogue, especially the ontology service and the automatic annotation tools. These could help in answering questions about the source of an annotation for example. It is also worth looking at OLS

New Actions

Action all : update the 20 questions section on the wiki

Action Rodrigo & Carole : Check the public staging part of the wiki to approve content meant for general public

Action Rodrigo : mail Eric his set of questions to put on the wiki

Action Jits/Thomas/Eric : Plan for effort to spend developing know-how to effectively use solr. Possibly investigate other ways of using the server with/without the acts_as_solr plugin

Action Jits/Eric : Investigate how to add some form of classification of the services

Upcoming Meetings

* Developer F2F at Manchester, week of the 19th

AOB

There will be a demo at the Strategic Advisory Board Meeting in February

There is potential for collaboration with Microsoft. Initial discussions on-going with Carole

Jit doing a presentation on BioCatalogue on the 29th

Previous/Next Meetings

Previous meeting: Phone Conference Meeting on Dec 16 2008

Next meeting:

Favourites Plugin

Available here: http://biocatalogue.rubyforge.org/svn/trunk/vendor/plugins/favourites/

IMPORTANT: you have to create a controller and model for favourites again in your app (but leaving them blank is fine though they can be used to extend the original ones from the plugin. AND use require_dependency (see examples of usage in BioCatalogue).

Controller depends on the presence of login_required, logged_in? and current_user methods (these should be in your application controller). The current_user method MUST return nil if no user is currently logged in.

Whilst running in development mode, if you get an error such as: ”A copy of ApplicationController has been removed from the module tree but is still active!”, then restart your server. This is due to the way Rails autoloads files in development mode, which affects the plugin and any extensions in the main app (eg: {app_root}/app/models/favourite.rb).

Dependencies

Gem: plugin_test_helper (in order to run the tests for the plugin).

Data Model

Entities

Favourites

Table name: favourites

Fields:

id

favouritable_type

favouritable_id

user_id

created_at

updated_at

This page is now deprecated. Please do not update!

Anyone can easily register Web Services

Instantly available to the community, developers and search engines

Service providers can advertise, describe and monitor their services

Registering Web Services in the BioCatalogue

Any registered users (members) can submit any Web Service to the BioCatalogue. You do not have to be the provider of the service to submit it to the BioCatalogue. Click here to become a Member of the BioCatalogue.

Currently the BioCatalogue support SOAP, REST and Soaplab services.

Submitting SOAP service to the BioCatalogue

Given that most existing SOAP services have a WSDL document, registering a SOAP service entry into the BioCatalogue requires only the WSDL url. The BioCatalogue WSDL parser automatically structures the data from the WSDL file. To submit a SOAP service with a defined WSDL file:

Select 'SOAP' from the 'Register a Service' page in the BioCatalogue

Paste your WSDL url in the form and click preview

Provide additional description to the service. This is optional but very useful. You may add these descriptions after you submit the service

Click 'Submit' to submit your service

Once the service is successfully submitted you can add more annotation (descriptions, tags, example values) to the service and its operations, inputs or outputs.

Submitting REST service to the BioCatalogue

The BioCatalogue has a basic support for REST service. To submit a REST service all you need is the REST endpoint and the service name.

Select 'REST' from the 'Register a Service' page in the BioCatalogue

Paste the endpoint URL

Provide a name for the service

Provide additional description for the service. This is optional but very useful. You may add these descriptions after you submit the service

Click 'Submit' to submit your service

Once the service is successfully submitted you can add more annotation (descriptions, tags, example values) to the service

Submitting Soaplab service to the BioCatalogue

Soaplab service are command line application wrapped as Web Services.

To submit a soaplab 1 service:

From the soaplab server which may look like <base URL/axis/services> look for 'AnalysisFactory' and copy the corresponding WSDL

Select 'Soaplab Server' from the 'Register a Service' page in the BioCatalogue

Paste the WSDL URL you have copied in the form and click preview

Click 'Submit' to submit your service

To submit a soaplab 2 service:

From the soaplab server copy the WSDL ending with <services/list?wsdl>

Select 'Soaplab Server' from the 'Register a Service' page in the BioCatalogue

Paste the WSDL URL you have copied in the form and click preview

Click 'Submit' to submit your service

Note that it may take a little while for all services to be registered.
Once the service is successfully submitted you can add more annotation (descriptions, tags, example values) to the service and its operations, inputs or outputs.